ANNE XIE

EDTECH ASSOCIATE PRODUCT MANAGER

EDUCATION

MS IN EDUCATIONAL TECHNOLOGY & APPLIED LEARNING SCIENCE

Carnegie Mellon University - Aug 2018 GPA: 3.94

BS IN EDUCATION & SOCIAL POLICY

Northwestern University - Jun 2016 GPA: 3.61; Majors: Mathematical Methods in the Social Sciences, Learning and Organizational Change

HONORS

HONORS THESIS (2ND PLACE EXPO POSTER) Northwestern University - Jun 2016

Characteristics of Mentoring Relationships in Massively Multiplayer Online Role-Playing Games

SKILLS

DESIGN RESEARCH

Contextual Inquiry, Cognitive Task Analysis, Usability Testing, Ethnographic Methods

SOFTWARE

Tableau, Storyline, Photoshop, Unity, MS Office, Qualtrics, Pentaho DI/BI Server

PROGRAMMING

SQL, Python, R, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bash/Shell, C#, Django

CONTACT

Email: annexie88@gmail.com Phone: (732) 429-4505

Portfolio: mintnip.github.io LinkedIn: annexie

PROFILE

Results-driven edtech master's graduate with strong communication, teamwork, research, analysis, & technical skills. Desires to jumpstart edtech career in an associate-level Product / Operations role with an open-minded team to create motivating learning experiences that open up new opportunities for learners.

EXPERIENCE

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY | JAN 2018 - PRESENT Capstone Project Coordinator & Scrum Product Owner

- Redesigning global training program for large professional services firm
- Supports designer, researcher, content directors, and developer to co-create product and strategy that meets client, course, and team needs

INQUIDIA CONSULTING (acquired by Hitachi Vantara) | AUG 2016 - JUL 2017 Business Intelligence Consultant & ETL Developer

- Built open source ETL solutions using Pentaho Data Integration for clients
- · Migrated multiregional Oracle data warehouses to Snowflake platform
- Built automated reports sourcing data from MySQL & MongoDB databases

SONIC LAB AT NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY | OCT 2014 - JUN 2016 Virtual Worlds & Multi-Team Systems Undergraduate Researcher

- Empirically modeled players' social networks using 1TB of game server data
- Coordinated 20-person lab experiments studying how 4 physically-separated teams optimize joint performance both in-person & via Skype

SIMPLERELEVANCE (acquired by Rise Interactive) | JUN 2015 - AUG 2015 Data Science Intern

- Implemented clients' business rules into item recommendation engine
- Wrote external-facing blog posts & internal guides and presented on projects to make technical machine learning knowledge accessible for marketers
- Created NLP search classifier trained on client's user-inputted search history

SLALOM CONSULTING | JAN 2015 - MAR 2015 Innovation & Insights Consultant Intern

- · Coordinated internal initiatives to engage Chicago consultants on the bench
- Designed AngularJS end-to-end tests for multimillion dollar client's web app

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY ARCHERY CLUB | NOV 2012 - MAR 2016 President/Founder/Webmaster